Guide to the Fletcher Nelson Papers, 1901-1981 UA.29.02.0226
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Fletcher Nelson papers
1901-1981
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Nelson, Fletcher
Duke University. Divinity School
UA.29.02.0226
4 Linear Feet
This collection contains the papers of Dr. Fletcher Nelson, a Methodist minister and Assistant to the Dean of Development of the Duke Divinity School. It consists entirely of subject files and notes for the sermons Dr. Nelson gave during his career as a minister.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of two series, the first of which consists of subject files containing publications related to topics on which Dr. Nelson preached. The second series consists of sermons Dr. Nelson wrote and gave while he was an active minister in Greensboro, Rutherfordton, Forest City, Morganton, and Charlotte, North Carolina.
Provenance
The Fletcher Nelson Papers were received by the Duke University Archives as a transfer in March, 1986.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Biographical Note
Dr. Fletcher Nelson was born on August 29, 1904. After completing his undergraduate studies at Hendrix College, he enrolled at Duke University Divinity School in 1927 and graduated with a B.D. in 1930. Upon his graduation, Dr. Nelson was ordained deacon on trial in the Western North Carolina Conference, and two years later he received elder's orders and was made a full member of the conference. He was a pastor in a variety of parishes in North Carolina until 1950. In 1952, he received the Doctor of Divinity Degree, honoris causa, from Duke University Divinity School. In 1964, he was appointed Assistant to the Dean of Development at Duke University Divinity School and stayed in that position until his retirement in 1971. Dr. Nelson died on February 8, 1981.
Methodist Church -- Sermons; Nelson, Fletcher; Duke University. Divinity School
- Subject Files, 1901-1981; 1
  - Dr. Fletcher Nelson Memorial Services, Sermon, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Christmas, 1946-1979 (Box 1)
  - Lent, Cross, Palm Sunday, Holy Week, Good Friday, 1935-1963 (Box 1)
  - Suffering and Sorrow, 1939-1962 (Box 1)
  - Easter and Easter Service, 1936-1966 (Box 1)
  - Christian Home and Family, 1933-1946 (Box 1)
  - New Year (Church and Calendar) and Watch Night, 1932-1945 (Box 1)
  - Christianity and Social Concerns (General), 1934-1944 (Box 1)
  - The Church and Labor, 1945-1946 (Box 1)
  - Race Relations, 1901-1946 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol, 1936-1948 (Box 1)
  - War and Peace (Armistice Day and July 4th), 1930-1947 (Box 1)
  - Sunday Observance, 1941-1945 (Box 1)
  - Baccalaureate and Graduation, 1939-1947 (Box 1)
  - Stewardship of Property, 1933-1967 (Box 1)
  - Missions, 1940-1950 (Box 1)
  - The Church, 1939-1968 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Day, 1940-1967 (Box 1)
  - Prayer, 1939-1946 (Box 1)
  - Thanksgiving, 1930-1963 (Box 1)
  - The Bible, 1932-1942 (Box 1)
  - Holy Spirit, Pentecost, 1930-1949 (Box 1)
  - Sacrament of Lord's Supper, 1938-1946 (Box 1)
  - Dedication and Installation Services, 1930-1942 (Box 1)
  - Scouts, 1943-1946 (Box 1)
  - Evangelism: Being a Christian (Sin - Repentance - Forgiveness), 1940-1965 (Box 1)
  - Faith and Belief, 1943-1948 (Box 1)
  - Worship, 1935-1942 (Box 1)
  - Love, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Ten Commandments, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Jesus Christ: The Man, 1932-1937 (Box 1)
  - Jesus Christ: The Message, 1935-1944 (Box 1)
  - God, 1941-1947 (Box 1)
  - Methodism, 1930-1963 (Box 1)
  - Church and State, 1946-1957 (Box 1)
  - Higher Education, 1945-1971; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Protestantism and Romanism, 1967 (Box 1)
- Sermon Notes, 1926-1966; 2
  - Communion Mediations, 1933 August (Box 1)
  - Thanksgiving Sermon, 1933 (Box 1)
  - A Vital Part of Worship, Finance or Christian Giving, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Prepare to Meet Thy God, 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - The Master is Come, 1930-1933 (Box 1)
  - Wanted: Spiritual Power: Needed, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - Reality in Religion, 1931 (Box 1)
  - The Model Church, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - America's Two Disappointments, 1931-1940 (Box 1)
  - Is it Easy or Hard to be Good, 1945-1948 (Box 1)
  - The Absurdity of Christianity, 1931-1933 (Box 1)
  - World's Bid for a Man, 1933-1948 (Box 1)
  - What Can Religion Do for Us?, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Freedom in Jesus Christ, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - And When They Had Prayed, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Why Are You Not a Christian, 1930-1931 (Box 1)
  - A Quest for Souls, circa 1930-1935 (Box 1)
  - A Good Man, circa 1930-1935 (Box 1)
  - Where Art Thou, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - A Needed Crusade, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Demos and Paul, 1931-1948 (Box 1)
  - Challenge of Jesus Christ, 1931-1948 (Box 1)
  - Privileges of Friendship, 1931-1947 (Box 1)
  - What Kind of a Christian Are You?, 1931-1948 (Box 1)
  - Simple Christianity and Ours, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Remember Jesus, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Jesus Conception of Righteousness, 1932 (Box 1)
  - What Crucified Jesus, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Glory of Despair, circa 1930-1933 (Box 1)
  - Philip the Evangelist, 1940 (Box 1)
  - After the Depression, What?, 1933 (Box 1)
  - A Definite Church Need, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - Moses: A Quality of Greatness, 1933-1948 (Box 1)
  - A Reception of Jesus, 1931-1933 (Box 1)
  - Greatest of World Powers, Love, 1933-1948 (Box 1)
  - Faith as a World Force, 1933 August (Box 1)
  - Rules of the Church, 1930 (Box 1)
  - The Tests of Life, Graduation, 1933-1948 (Box 1)
  - Relation of John to Jesus, 1933-1948 (Box 1)
  - The Salvation Sentence, 1933 (Box 1)
  - The Educational Task of the Local Church, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Needed: A Victory Complex, 1933 (Box 1)
  - The Divine Magnet, 1932 December (Box 1)
  - Why I Vote Against Repeal, 1933 (Box 1)
  - The Last Radiance, circa 1933 (Box 1)
  - The Message of the Bible, 1933-1945 (Box 1)
  - The Two Census Books, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Paul, The Track Coach, circa 1933 (Box 1)
  - The Volunteer, Isaiah, 1945-1949 (Box 1)
  - A Communion Meditation, 1933 December (Box 1)
  - We Do Our Part, A New Year's Message, 1933 (Box 1)
  - A Land of Hills and Valleys, circa 1933 (Box 1)
  - The Mission and Message of Jesus, circa 1933 (Box 1)
  - A Personal Confession of Faith, 1934 January (Box 1)
  - Making the Cap Fit, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Some of Life's Foundation Rocks, 1933 (Box 2)
  - A Broken Vow, circa 1933 (Box 2)
  - The Angle of Repose, 1933 (Box 2)
  - Two Sons of Their Father, circa 1934 (Box 2)
  - Jesus' Way of Life, 1945-1948 (Box 2)
  - A Lesson in Stewardship, circa 1934 (Box 2)
  - A Study in Courses, 1933 (Box 2)
  - Why Did Jesus Have Himself Crucified?, 1934 March (Box 2)
  - How May We Interpret the Cross?, 1934-1949 (Box 2)
  - Flowers from Gethsemane, 1934 March (Box 2)
  - Questions About Life, 1934-1949 (Box 2)
  - What is Christianity, 1934 April (Box 2)
  - The Perils of Prayer, circa 1934 (Box 2)
  - An Interpretation of Christ's 'Follow Me', circa 1934 (Box 2)
  - The Meaning of Mother's Day, 1932-1944 (Box 2)
  - Come Holy Spirit, 1934 (Box 2)
  - An Interpretation of Christ's 'Follow Me' II, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Lord's Supper: Its Nature and Significant, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - What Makes a Great Church?, 1933-1937 (Box 2)
  - The Adequacy of Christianity, 1930-1948 (Box 2)
  - Two Men at Prayer, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - A Man and His Money, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Crowing of the Cock: A Communion Meditation, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Why Did Jesus Choose the Cross, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - In Interest of Kingdom Extension, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Why I Believe in Mission, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Is the Church Ready for a Revival?, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Necessity of Vision, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - On Human Forgiveness, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Renovating Humanity's Garment, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Act of Living Commencement, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - A Christian in My Heart, circa 1930-1948 (Box 2)
  - Parable of the Four Sails, circa 1930-1949 (Box 2)
  - Achieving a Life of Faith, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Dying Fire, circa 1930-1946 (Box 2)
  - "Forward March!" A Sermon for Installation or New Year, 1934 (Box 2)
  - If I Had Only One Sermon to Preach, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - A Father's Heart Revealed, 1930 (Box 2)
  - The Reason for Living, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Unknown Soldier Speaks, 1932 (Box 2)
  - The Program of the Upper Room, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Crowded Out Christ Evangelistic, Christmas, circa 1930-1945 (Box 2)
  - The Tragedy of Lukewarmness, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Making People Care, circa 1930-1948 (Box 2)
  - Holy Habits, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Essence of Christmas, circa 1930-1945 (Box 2)
  - The Parable of the Talents, circa 1930-1949 (Box 2)
  - A Man Who Came Back, Evangelistic, New Year, circa 1930-1948 (Box 2)
  - "A Friend at Midnight" or "The Embarrassed Host", circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - A Beautiful Work, Mary of Bethany, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Life and Trouble, circa 1930-1949 (Box 2)
  - One Year of Repeal, circa 1933 (Box 2)
  - What Do You Do with Your Dreams?, circa 1930-1949 (Box 2)
  - A Seeker After Pearls, circa 1930-1949 (Box 2)
  - Christ and the Lost, circa 1930-1944 (Box 2)
  - A Communion Meditation, circa 1930-1944 (Box 2)
  - Let Us Worship God, 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Are You a Methodist, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Those Who Trespass, circa 1930-1948 (Box 2)
  - In Interest of Missions, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - God's Willingness and Eagerness to Forgive and Forget, circa 1930-1947 (Box 2)
  - Crucified by Stupidity, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Concerning the Cross, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Meditations on 1,4,7 Words from Cross, Good Friday Service, circa 1930-1939 (Box 2)
  - And Endless Life (Easter), circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Church Teachers, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Perpetuating Pentecost, 1935-1943 (Box 2)
  - The Voice of a Trumpet, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - A Faith That Sings, circa 1930-1949 (Box 2)
  - Sacrament of the Embroidered Handkerchief, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Laughing Fool, The Mocker, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - When Life Tumbles In, What Then?, 1934 (Box 2)
  - A Most Amazing Request, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Are We Hiding From God?, circa 1930-1949 (Box 2)
  - How May We Find God, circa 1930-1946 (Box 2)
  - The Sermon in the Sacrament, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - How May We Know We Have Found God?, circa 1930-1946 (Box 2)
  - The Tragedy of Uselessness, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Temptation, Struggle, Victory, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Jesus' Estimate of the Kingdom's Worth, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - There's a Lad Here, circa 1930-1948 (Box 2)
  - Confession of a Prodigal, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - "We", circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Untrodden Way, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Peace, War, 1935 (Box 2)
  - The Master's Way with Failures, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Why Should I Commune?, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Secrets, circa 1935 (Box 2)
  - Concerning the Bible, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - What the Church Needs Most, circa 1930-1949 (Box 2)
  - Beautiful Ideals and Brutal Facts, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Challenge of the Church, 1935-1949 (Box 2)
  - Kagawa: His Religion and Life, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Ways to Tell Right from Wrong, circa 1930-1949 (Box 2)
  - A Communion Meditation, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Hills of Religion, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Lamb of God, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Getting Through Life's Hard Places, circa 1930-1949 (Box 2)
  - Jephthah, A Man Who Paid A Vow, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Life Made Over Again, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Why I Believe in God, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Giving the Highest a Hearing, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - A Man Whom Jesus Lost, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Why I Believe in Jesus, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Why I Believe in the Bible, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Forgiveness of Sins, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Life After Life, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - A Faith That is Remarkable, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - His Hands, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Ye Are My Witnesses, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - Some Lessons From Gideon's Experience, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Race Not to the Swift, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - The Symbolism of the Sacrament, circa 1930-1948 (Box 2)
  - Where is Able Thy Brother?, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
  - A Family Talk About Essentials or the Supreme Gift, circa 1935-1949 (Box 2)
  - Please Excuse Me, circa 1935-1943 (Box 2)
  - Father Did It (Father's Day Sermon), circa 1935 (Box 2)
  - The Second Mile, 1938 (Box 2)
  - The Fruits of Righteousness, 1935-1949 (Box 2)
  - Christ's Borrowings, circa 1935 (Box 2)
  - The Art of Inattention, 1936 (Box 2)
  - The Interest on the Rutherfordton Church Debt, circa 1935 (Box 2)
  - Wake Up and Live, 1936 (Box 2)
  - The Lost Christ, circa 1935-1945 (Box 2)
  - The Return of the Syrians, circa 1935 (Box 2)
  - The Task of Forgetting, circa 1935 (Box 2)
  - A Communion Meditation (5 Parts) (stories), circa 1935 (Box 2)
  - My Neighbor, circa 1935-1948 (Box 2)
  - Christian Growth in the Home, circa 1935 (Box 2)
  - What I Expect of my Church, 1936 (Box 2)
  - A Tragic If, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - The Challenge of a New Conference Year, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - The Individual Conscience and War, circa 1935-1938 (Box 2)
  - Creative Education, 1936-1942 (Box 2)
  - A Communion Meditation, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - Practicing the Presence, 1937 (Box 2)
  - The Secret of Victorious Living, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - Rejoicing in Hope, 1936-1941 (Box 2)
  - Keeping Christmas in the Heart, 1932-1947 (Box 2)
  - The Power to See It Through, circa 1935-1949 (Box 2)
  - The First Commandment, circa 1935 (Box 2)
  - These Things I Will Keep, 1936 (Box 2)
  - The Liquor Situation Today (1937) (Box 2)
  - The Missionary Motive, 1936, August (Box 2)
  - Passing Through the Needle's Eye, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - The Second Commandment (Revised), circa 1935-1943 (Box 2)
  - The Man Who Owned the Upper Room, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - The Third Commandment, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - The Fourth Commandment, circa 1935-1943 (Box 2)
  - The New Day in a World of Change, 1936 November (Box 2)
  - Christian Living in a World of Change, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - The Fifth Commandment, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - The Sixth Commandment, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - The Noble Seven Hundred, circa 1935-1947 (Box 2)
  - The Seventh Commandment, circa 1935-1943 (Box 2)
  - On Going a Little Further, 1936-1943 (Box 2)
  - The Inevitable Cross, 1937-1945 (Box 2)
  - Earning the Right to Eternal Life, 1936-1949 (Box 2)
  - The Eighth Commandment, "Thou Shalt Not Steal", circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - The Ninth Commandment, circa 1935-1943 (Box 2)
  - The Bishop's Crusade, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - The Tenth Commandment, circa 1935-1945 (Box 2)
  - Is it Worth While?, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - Mothers and Children, 1933 May (Box 2)
  - A Communion Meditation, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - I'm Not Going to Church Today, 1937-1946 (Box 2)
  - The Gamaliel Stood Up, 1936-1949 (Box 2)
  - The Church of the Living God, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - Men and Their Shadows, 1934-1948 (Box 2)
  - One Thing Thou Lackest, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - What is Your Religion Doing For Others, 1937-1948 (Box 2)
  - A Communion Service (in 5 parts - poems), circa 1935-1948 (Box 2)
  - The Great Invitation, 1936-1947 (Box 2)
  - The Evangelistic Mission of Meditation, 1936-1942 (Box 2)
  - How Revivals Come, 1936 (Box 2)
  - He Shall Winneth Souls, 1937 February (Box 2)
  - Partners, 1935-1948 (Box 2)
  - Sainthood, 1937 (Box 2)
  - A Famous Inscription, 1936-1948 (Box 2)
  - Where are the Nine?, 1937-1948 (Box 2)
  - A Common Meditation, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - Arise, Go Over This Jordan, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - Let Us Give Thanks (Thanksgiving), 1936-1947 (Box 2)
  - Glorifying and Praising Sermon for Sunday after Christmas Sunday, 1937-1948 (Box 2)
  - God at the Gateway, A New Year's Sermon, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Where God and Man Meet, 1937-1947 (Box 2)
  - John Wesley Before Aldersgate, circa 1935-1936 (Box 2)
  - Aldersgate! What Happened?, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Tensions in Personal Life, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - Can We Repeat Aldersgate?, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Let's Make Our Highways Safe, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Just a Talk, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - Preparedness, circa 1935-1948 (Box 2)
  - The Tragedies of Silence, 1938 March (Box 2)
  - The Conditions of Aldersgate, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Wesley's Legacy After 200 years, 1938 (Box 2)
  - God in the Storm, 1935-1949 (Box 2)
  - God's Challenge to Man, 1937 (Box 2)
  - A Talk About Money, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - A Good Man's Blunder, 1935-1943 (Box 2)
  - A Family Talk, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - The Power to Love, 1935 (Box 2)
  - On Being Happy, circa 1935-1941 (Box 2)
  - On Rising to One's Best Self, circa 1935-1949 (Box 2)
  - For Annual Pledge Day, 1938 (Box 2)
  - A Church Member and His Civic Responsibility, 1933 (Box 2)
  - Why Go to Church?, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Work for Everyone, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Armistice Day Reflections, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Facing the New Year, 1938-1947 (Box 2)
  - If These Things Be True, Then, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - There is No Tomorrow, 1938-1946 (Box 2)
  - The Great Business of Being Christian, circa 1935-1946 (Box 2)
  - Living to Meet the Deepest Needs, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - Worst Thing That Ever Happened to Jesus, 1933-1949 (Box 2)
  - All Things Are Yours, circa 1935-1947 (Box 2)
  - I Join the Church, circa 1935-1942 (Box 2)
  - The Land Beyond, circa 1935-1947 (Box 2)
  - Lamps Without Oil, circa 1935-1947 (Box 2)
  - Spirit of Christ the Test of Genuine Discipleship, 1935-1949 (Box 2)
  - A Lesson from the Parable of the Barren Fig Tree, circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - A Communion Meditation (In 10 parts), circa 1935-1940 (Box 2)
  - The Pioneer of Life, 1935-1948 (Box 2)
  - Avenues Which Lead to God, 1935-1936 (Box 2)
  - The Nature and Reality of God, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Does God Guide?, 1936 May (Box 2)
  - What Memorial Have You?, 1939-1948 (Box 2)
  - This Church and the Future, circa 1935-1949 (Box 2)
  - When God Stands By, Or the Challenge of Pain, 1939 (Box 2)
  - The Challenge of Our History, 1930 (Box 2)
  - A Christian in a World at War, 1939 (Box 2)
  - And a Man Shall Be, 1933-1949 (Box 2)
  - The Bible, Is it Worthwhile, circa 1939-1947 (Box 3)
  - He Could Not Be His or the Unhidden Christ, circa 1940-1941 (Box 3)
  - A Church Christ Can Use, circa 1940-1946 (Box 3)
  - The Meaning of Lent, 1939-1948 (Box 3)
  - The Love Affairs of Youth, 1940-1948 (Box 3)
  - What is Important to You?, 1940-1947 (Box 3)
  - What I Expect of My Young People, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Let the Church be the Church, circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - Leisure and the Abundant Life, 1940-1948 (Box 3)
  - Dawn, Easter Sermon, 1936-1949 (Box 3)
  - A Fellowship Church, circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - The Church Facing a World of Pessimism, circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - Perils and Possibilities of Disillusionment, circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - Thinking Aloud in War Times, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Will Spirit Win?, circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - Thankful For What? (Thanksgiving Sermon), 1939 (Box 3)
  - Hunt: "Light of the World", circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - Hofman: Christ and Rich Young Man, circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - Will a Man Rob God?, circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - Millet: The Sower, circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - Hoffman: Christ in Gethsemane, circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - The Seeking God, circa 1941 (Box 3)
  - God Our Ally, circa 1941 (Box 3)
  - Why Try?, 1940-1949 (Box 3)
  - Florence Nightingale, The Tests of Life, circa 1940-1945 (Box 3)
  - This I Believe And?, 1941 (Box 3)
  - A Questionnaire, 1937 (Box 3)
  - The Loving Cup of Christians, Communion Meditation, circa 1940-1944 (Box 3)
  - A Strong Church for a Hard World, circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - Build a Bigger Life, circa 1940-1945 (Box 3)
  - The Unconquerable Spirit of a Great City, circa 1940 (Box 3)
  - Deepening Our Faith in God's Love and Care, circa 1940-1949 (Box 3)
  - Education for Defense, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Only a Layman, 1940-1948 (Box 3)
  - Living One's Daily Life With God, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Soord: The Lost Sheep, circa 1941 (Box 3)
  - A Christian Prays in Times Like These (Armistice Day), 1941 (Box 3)
  - The Presence (Gospel in Art Series), circa 1941 (Box 3)
  - Bloch: "Come Unto Me", 1945 (Box 3)
  - A Christmas Vesper Service, 1938-1941 (Box 3)
  - Watch-Night Service, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Longing for Communion (Communion Meditation), circa 1941-1947 (Box 3)
  - Keep Your Christian Faith!, circa 1941 (Box 3)
  - My Church, 1942-1948 (Box 3)
  - When Great Events Make Common Tasks Seem Trivial, 1942-1944 (Box 3)
  - The Church and War, circa 1942 (Box 3)
  - Bringing God Into the Daily Records, 1942-1948 (Box 3)
  - Jesus Christ: Dead or Alive? Easter, 1939-1945 (Box 3)
  - The Hidden Years, Mother's Day, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Remember Jesus Christ (Communion Meditation), circa 1940-1945 (Box 3)
  - The Ministry of Encouragement, 1942-1948 (Box 3)
  - Liquor and the War, 1942 July (Box 3)
  - Learning How to Handle Our Troubles, circa 1940-1948 (Box 3)
  - Facing Life With Jesus Christ, 1942 (Box 3)
  - The Judgment and Mercy of God, 1942 (Box 3)
  - In the Midst of Them, 1942-1944 (Box 3)
  - Things That Belong to Peace, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Grace, 1942-1946 (Box 3)
  - The Gospel is Adequate, 1942-1948 (Box 3)
  - Belief and Faith, 1942 (Box 3)
  - The Alabaster Box of Christmas, 1942 (Box 3)
  - A Christmas Candle Lighting Service, 1943 (Box 3)
  - Watch Night Service, circa 1943-1947 (Box 3)
  - Communion Meditation for New Years Day, 1944-1945 (Box 3)
  - The Church and It's Program in a World at War, 1943 January (Box 3)
  - These My Brethren (Missionary - Brotherhood), 1943 February (Box 3)
  - Personalities of Pontius Pilate (Evangelistic), 1943-1948 (Box 3)
  - Personalities of the Passion: Barabbas, 1943-1948 (Box 3)
  - Personalities of the Passion: Judas, 1943-1948 (Box 3)
  - Flandrin: Christ Mourns Over the City, 1943 (Box 3)
  - Personalities of the Passion: Herod, circa 1943-1948 (Box 3)
  - Da Vinci: The Last Supper, circa 1943 (Box 3)
  - Dismas, The Crucified Revolutionary, 1943 (Box 3)
  - Armitage: The Remorse of Judas, circa 1943 (Box 3)
  - Harrach: Peter's Denial, circa 1943 (Box 3)
  - Munkacsy: Christ on Calvary, circa 1943 (Box 3)
  - Joseph of Arimethea (Easter Sermon), 1943-1949 (Box 3)
  - Mary the Mother of Jesus (Mother's Day)q, 1943-1947 (Box 3)
  - Christian Giving (Finances), 1943-1949 (Box 3)
  - A Serene Spirit in Strenuous Times, 1943-1948 (Box 3)
  - Let's Take a Look at the Church, circa 1943 (Box 3)
  - All This and Heaven Too, circa 1943 (Box 3)
  - The Way of Jesus for Our World, circa 1943-1948 (Box 3)
  - Majoring on Minors, circa 1943-1946 (Box 3)
  - Behold this Dreamer Cometh, 1942-1943 (Box 3)
  - Religious Basis of a Just and Durable Peace, 1943 (Box 3)
  - Faith in God is Essential, 1943-1948 (Box 3)
  - When Ye Pray, 1943-1949 (Box 3)
  - The Pool of Bethesda, 1940-1949 (Box 3)
  - You Can't Live But One Way, 1943-1948 (Box 3)
  - The Supreme Meaning of Christmas, 1943-1948 (Box 3)
  - Mister Fix-It, 1937-1944 (Box 3)
  - Argue with the Great Commission, But, 1944-1948 (Box 3)
  - Jesus Measures a Man, 1944 (Box 3)
  - Let Him Be Your Minister, 1944-1947 (Box 3)
  - From Victory to Peace, 1944 (Box 3)
  - The Retreat Must Stop, 1944-1945 (Box 3)
  - God is Always There, 1944 (Box 3)
  - The Language of the Cross, 1944 (Box 3)
  - God is Stronger Than Death (Easter), 1944 (Box 3)
  - Get Back Into the Game, 1943-1948 (Box 3)